pendleton-usa.com 2017-09-30

# Privacy & Security

####  Whether you're purchasing online or just browsing, your privacy is important to us. Please take the time to review Pendleton's policy for handling your customer information. By visiting the Pendleton website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Pendleton's Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please revisit this page and review the Policy regularly. If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us via e-mail at [_pendletoncatalog@penwool.com_](mailto:pendletoncatalog@penwool.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy). We appreciate your comments and suggestions. 

Pendleton may share the information it collects with third parties, as detailed below. We may use the information to improve the content of our website, to make our future marketing efforts more efficient, to notify you about current Pendleton products, special offers, services and events, and for other purposes. The information we collect may be combined with other personally identifiable information available from our records and other sources, such as purchase history and demographic information.

Your trust and privacy are very important to us! Therefore, we ask only for the information we need to process your requests:

**Postal Address**  
If you purchase from us or request a Pendleton catalog by mail, we will need a postal address, and we will add your name to our mailing list. Occasionally, we may also share your name with select companies whose services or products are similar to Pendleton's. If you do not want to receive our catalog by mail or do not want your name shared with other companies, just let us know by calling 1-800-649-1512 or faxing us at 503-535-5502, or 

[_send us an e-mail_](mailto:pendletoncatalog@penwool.com?subject=Do%20Not%20Share). 

**Phone Number**  
We ask for your phone number on the order form in the event we need to contact you regarding your order. We will not otherwise call you, and we will not share your phone number with any other companies. 

**Credit Card Information**  
To purchase from the Pendleton website, you will need to give us a credit card number. This information is kept encrypted during your order to ensure secure purchases. 

**E-Mail Address**  
If you would like to receive e-mail on what's new at the Pendleton site, fill out our e-mail registration page, or give us your e-mail address at checkout, and we will add you to our mailing list. If you subscribe to Pendleton's e-mail list, we will send you periodic updates and news about our website. We will also use the e-mail address you provide on your order to send you website updates. Please be assured that the e-mail address you provide to Pendleton is for internal use only.

If you decide you would like to be removed from this service, you may follow the instructions on the messages you are sent, call us at 1-800-649-1512, send a fax to 503-535-5502, or 

[_send us an e-mail_](mailto:pendletoncatalog@penwool.com?subject=Do%20Not%20E-mail). 

**Gift Messages:**  
You may choose to include a gift message with your online purchase. We will include the note when we deliver the gift to the recipient address you provide. We will not otherwise disclose the note to anyone.

**Questions and Comments:**  
We want to hear from you -- your comments, suggestions, questions. Every message is read and a response sent as quickly as possible if requested. The information you send us is used to respond to your questions and comments only. You may send your comments, suggestions or questions to Pendleton Woolen Mills Customer Service Dept., P.O. Box 3030, Portland, OR 97208, or 

[_send an e-mail to our Customer Service Department_](mailto:pendletoncatalog@penwool.com?subject=Questions%20and%20Comments).

**Cookies:**  
Pendleton may also use "cookies" or other means to passively collect information about your use of our website. A cookie is a piece of data stored on your computer that lets your web browser talk with Pendleton's web server. For example, cookies save you from retyping your user name and password every time you use our secure checkout. If you are shopping on the Pendleton site and are having difficulty completing your order, please check the privacy settings in your browser. If you have your settings set to not accept cookies, you will not be able to purchase from the Pendleton site. Pendleton may also use "cookies" provided by our (agent, third party agency, provider) or other means to passively collect information about your use of our website. 

**Third Party Vendors:**  
We may also from time to time contract with third party vendors to serve ads to our customers on our behalf across the Internet or to send our catalogs to customers whom we think may be interested in our products or services. To do this, the vendors will collect anonymous information about your visits to our Web site and your interaction with our products and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie or pixel tag – industry standard technology used by most major Web sites. No personally identifiable information is collected in this process. Our vendors may also pool the anonymous information that they collect with other sources of information not collected during your visit to our website, which may include your name and mailing address, for purposes of determining whether you might be interested in receiving a catalog. If you do not wish for cookies or pixel tags to be placed on your computer, most commercially available web browsers permit you to prevent that from taking place. 

**Children:**  
The Pendleton website is intended only for those aged 13 and older. If you are under 13, you may not register or submit personally identifiable information on, to or through the site. Pendleton does not collect personally identifiable information from any person Pendleton knows to be under 13.

**Opting Out:**  
If you do not wish to receive our printed catalog, if you do not wish to receive promotional e-mail from Pendleton, or if you do not wish your name to be shared with third parties for marketing purposes, please contact us via e-mail at 

[_pendletoncatalog@penwool.com_](mailto:pendletoncatalog@penwool.com?subject=Opt%20Out).

**Security:**  
Pendleton takes care to protect the security of your personal information, including your credit card information, from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure. However, transmissions to the website may be intercepted and read by others and Pendleton cannot be responsible for any such interception.

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect the security of your personal on-line order information. To check the security of your connection to our website, look in the lower right-hand corner of your browser window after entering our checkout section. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser), then SSL is active. You can also double-check you are in a secure shopping environment by looking at the URL line of your browser. When you are using a secure server, the first characters of the site address will change from "http" to "https." If you cannot access the secure server for any reason, please call and place your order by phone at 1-800-649-1512. 

Effective May __ 2016
